MARLENA DOWNER

Mobile:07909484492 LinkedIn: Marlena Asantewah Downer

Email: marlenadowner@hotmail.co.uk

As a results-driven person, with a key eye for detail, I have made it a personal goal to switch into the Digital sector, this year. During lockdown of 2020, I started using Shopify to form a website called Candy Dipped but found there were limitations of the plug-ins provided. Subsequently, I developed an interest in Web development and UX and began researching code languages. I'm currently taking a 16-week bootcamp course on Front End Web Development with edX under the Skills for Life program. As a resilient individual, I believe hard work pays off and the bootcamp will be the perfect opportunity to bridge the gap into Tech.

KEY SKILLS

- Strong written and verbal communication
- Creative thinking
- Self-motivated
- Organised

- Problem solving
- Analytical
- Excellent team player

TECHNICAL LANGUAGES/SKILLS

(On completion of Front-End Wed Development bootcamp I would have been taught the following)

- HTML5
- CSS3
- Javascript
- UX + Bootstrap

- Web API's, Third API's and server API's
- Node.js
- React.js
- Github, Git and Netlify

EDUCATIONAL AND PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Front End Web Development Bootcamp- December 2022- March 2023 (present)

SKILLS FOR LIFE- ed X

University of Derby- September 2010- January 2014

BSc Hons Architectural Technology and Practices

Free2Learn

BTEC National Diploma Level 2 Customer Services

BTEC National Diploma Level 2 Team Leading and Management

Bromley College of Further and Higher Education

BTEC National Diploma- Building and Construction Level 3

Westwood Language College for Girls

9 GCSE's including English and Math's

WORK HISTORY

Front End Web Development Bootcamp (Present- 16 weeks)

Ed X-Skills for Life

December 2022- March 2023 (completion date)

Course topics include

Front-end fundamentals- HTML, JavaScript, CSS, UX, Git & Github, Information architecture and User experience design.

Modern front-end frameworks- Structuring, positioning, and optimisation of web page content, React.js and Netlify. **Developing with APIs-** Javascript framework, DOM manipulation, Web-based applications and Data extraction and retrieval.

Member Service's Advisor (Present)

Pension Protection Fund- Croydon, Surrey, July 2021- Present

Key Achievements

- **Business Testing Team BTT Bench**: I was selected to be part of testing bench/group to assist the Business Testing team during busy periods.
- Shadowing the IT department: I have been given the opportunity to shadow individuals across the IT department to learn of the various roles and what they entail

Key Responsibilities

- Handling calls from members, financial advisors, and third parties in line with the companies KPIs.
- Ensuring the personal information of members are accurate and in line with GDPR, using the Civica software.
- Discussing pension information with members in line with individual financial circumstances.
- Producing pension forecasts and illustrations, to aid in discussions surrounding retirement options.
- Tailoring my customer service approach to members in financial difficulty and showing empathy and compassion in bereavement cases.

Candy Dipped

Personal project March 2020- Present

Key Responsibilities

- Amending pre-existing codes to tailor the aesthetics of the website to the desired theme.
- Using plug in apps and tailoring them to users' needs i.e., Shipping Tracker.
- Learning the best practice of layouts and placements for the website.
- Conducting concept analysis to aid with the design of the website.
- Learning how to use Canva Pro to design pictures and videos for the web pages.

MAC- Motor Assistance Coordinator

Allianz Worldwide partners- Croydon, Surrey, November 2017- June 2021

Key Achievements

- **Promotion:** After receiving excellent feedback from customers and management, along with passing call audits and hitting individual KPI targets, I was promoted to Senior Coordinator.
- Training buddy: Training new joiners and acting in as their point of contact to resolve issues or queries.

Key Responsibilities

- Handling cases in a prompt and efficient manner in line with the company and client expectations, within specific time limits.
- Working as part of a team to ensure all department targets and service levels are met.
- Providing insight where due, to support improvements to the customer experience.
- Drawing on excellent communication skills to handle any customer complaints or concerns.
- Monitoring cases in the UK & abroad to ensure that customers receive the most appropriate service in a timely and cost-effective manner.
- Utilising various systems to administer bookings and customer accounts.

Architectural Assistant

iPlans- Staunton August 2017 – October 2017

Key Achievements

- **Property Surveyance**: Taking full survey and measurements of the client's properties to pass over to the CAD team, enabling them to start drawing up existing floor plans.
- Design and concept briefs: Showing my individual creativity and ideas with clients in the concept stages.

Key Responsibilities

- Attending design briefs with new clients: providing design sketches and concepts.
- Surveying client properties with Leica Disto and Site Master to produce floor plans, elevations, and sections in CAD.
- Reviewing elevations and sections of the drafting process with the drafting team and a senior surveyor.
- Assisting surveyors in alterations of designs in preparation for resubmission of planning permission.
- Liaising with building contractors and builders.